why is the sum of a positive real number
and its reciprocal always greater than
or equal to 2 let X be a positive real
number and draw a rectangle with
Dimensions X by 1 /x and create four
rotated copies like this each of these
rectangles has an area of 1x * X which
is 1 so the four rectangles each enclose
an area of one these four rectangles lie
inside of an x + 1X by x + 1X s
enclosing an area of the quantity x +
1x^2 the four rectangles almost never
fill the entire square there's a missing
sub Square inside and that means that x
+ 1X 2 is greater than or equal to 1 + 1
+ 1 + 1 which is equal to 4 taking the
square root of both sides and
remembering that X is positive means
that x + 1X is greater than or equal to
2 can you see how to use the Center
Square to produce a condition to
guarantee x + 1x equal 2